Tim Diggins

email tim@red56.co.uk http://red56.co.uk

Summary of key skills and experience

I am an developer, application designer, and manager with extensive experience in interactive systems design and production. I have design, management, and programming expertise in the web, mobile and multimedia arenas. To each of my consultancy engagements and employment roles I have brought my ability to forge links between different domains: ethnography and design, marketing and technology, artistic endeavour and technological opportunity.

Application programming and design

- Programming and design of web, mobile and desktop applications
- for a wide range of clients (from multinationals to one-man bands)
- in a range of teams (from full delivery to management of internal team with external resources (freelancers, technical consultants, translation agencies).

UI and Interaction Design

- UI and interface design since 1992 for a variety of clients (online information services, multinational technology companies, retail dairy farms and other SMEs)
- Requirements elicitation, early prototyping, lightweight methods
- Innovative and compelling prototypes of mobile device interfaces for research.

Business Management, Accountability, Project Management

- Profit and loss accountability for a £1m pa business (Teamworks Interactive Ltd), with 20 employees.
- Project managed and ensured completion of projects, ranging from £30k to £500k, for global delivery (e.g. for Hewlett Packard & Novartis Pharmaceuticals).

Industrial Research and European Collaboration

- Prepared, won, and managed a Technology Strategy Board "feasibility study" grant in the "Digital Britain" strand.
- Researched on domestic technology as part of a multi-disciplinary EU-funded project with Mixed Reality Lab, Nottingham and Philips Design, Amsterdam.
- Managed release of, and co-authored, deliverables for formal review.
- Fundamental HCI research experience in ubiquitous computing

Recent urls:

- http://permatime.com sole programmer [RoR]
- http://teamportfolios.com sole programmer [RoR]
- http://openstudiowestminster.org lead programmer [RoR]
- http://theconnectedrepublic.org lead programmer [RoR]
- http://culturetheque.com HTML and jQuery only
- http://sodaplay.com lead programmer [Java]
- https://challenge.networcs.net sole programmer [Java]

Employment

Clever Plugs Ltd, Founder (since 10.2008)

Clever Plugs Ltd. 5 Cowcross St. London EC1V 6DW

Developing a range of software products used in Broadcast production (chromakeying, 3d, format conversion, workflow management).

Independent Design and Technology Consultant (since 10.2007)

Design & programming for a variety of web projects (in Ruby on Rails and Java):

- Challenge Machine, a webapplication for teaching children internet literacy and safety for Worcestershire LA. https://challenge.networcs.net
- The Connected Republic social network and collaborative blogging site for Cisco. http://theconnectedrepublic.org
- Open Studios Westminister, a media aggregator and editorial system for the University of Westminster Architecture department's http://openstudiowestminster.org
- Permatime.com a tool to help coordinate action and timekeeping for distributed teams
- Teamportfolios.com an online linking portfolio site

Soda Creative, Technical Director (10.2004-12.2007)

Soda Creative Ltd, 17-25 Cremer St, London E2 8HD

Application design and programming - developing extensible desktop application framework, robotics application and social web applications. Also responsible for technical systems management, and modernizing development methodology.

Independent Design and Technology Consultant (05.2002-10.2004)

Design & programming for a variety of clients and projects:

- Application design & programming for a 3d financial simulation tool.
- Product design and interaction design consultancy (Instrata, Image Semantics)
- Interactive system design and development for sales tools (Hewlett Packard).
- Web design and marketing consultancy (Back in Action, Ballet.co).

Xerox Research Centre Europe, Research Scientist (03.2001-05.2002)

XRCE Cambridge, 61 Regent Street, Cambridge CB2 1AB

Design and UI expertise for a multi-disciplinary team comprising ethnographers, product designers, and technologists on specific European-funded project (MiME) and on "Mobile and Ubiquitous Services" research and development.

Teamworks, General Manager / New Media and Technology Director (1997-2001)

Teamworks, 46 Loman St, London SE1 0EH

Started up and managed this new media and web technology offshoot of marketing company Teamworks Advertising. Delivered eBusiness consultancy, new media planning, IA and design leadership to clients such as Hewlett Packard, Novartis Pharmaceuticals.

RED56, Founder and Director (1994-97)

RED56, 91 Brick Lane, London E1 6QN

Interactive solutions (database systems, interactive CDs, websites) for SMEs and corporate clients (Channel 4, Bristol Myers Squibb). Interactive art for public display with choreographer and composer collaborators (Sadlers Wells, South Bank).

HarperCollins Advanced Media, Technology Consultant (1993-4)

Product development and prototyping, and new media technology advice for new media division of HarperCollins publishers.

FT Profile Information, Interface Consultant (1992)

Human interface design guidelines for new online access for financial and news information service. Proposed and evangelised a revised UI.

Education

Chelsea College of Art and Design, BA (Hons 2:1) Fine Art (1990-1993)

Art specialisation with "Alternative Media", specific area: Installation/video/public art

Balliol College, Oxford, MSt. European Language and Literature (1986-88)

Post graduate taught course with two papers: Modern Greek Poetry 1911-1967, Methods of Criticism and Literary Theory

University of California Berkeley, BA (with a distinction in General Scholarship) *Humanities/Linguistics* (1983-86)

Undergraduate degree. Semiotics, Syntax, Semantics, Modern Greek, Medieval Welsh, Russian

Technologies

Foreground:

- Ruby, Ruby on Rails,
- Python
- Java (Spring, JSP, Tomcat, Servlets).
- Web stuff (REST, XML, Web services, HTML, JavaScript / jQuery, CSS)

Via:

- Test-driven, Agile, Iterative, Continuous Integration, Refactoring,
- Subversion, Git, Mercurial, CruiseControl, Eclipse
- MySQL, Apache,
- Mac / Windows / Linux / BSD

A while ago:

• Macromedia Director, Lingo, ActionScript, Perl, PHP, C#, .NET, Lisp, Pascal, Visual Basic, COM, MS-SQL Server, Omnis 5, Omnis 7, Filemaker Pro, Access

Publications

2003 Tolmie, P and Diggins, T., The home of the distant present? What understanding of domestic life is required by "smart homes"?, 1st UK-UbiNet Workshop, 25-26th September 2003, Imperial College London

2003 Diggins, T. and Tolmie, P., *The 'adequate' design of ethnographic outputs for practice: some explorations of the characteristics of design resources*, The Journal of Personal and Ubiquitous Computing, Volume 7 (3-4) July

2002 Tolmie, P., Pycock, J., Diggins, T., MacLean, A. and Karsenty, A. *Unremarkable computing*. In Proceedings of ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. Minneapolis, Minnesota, 2002.